Welcome back to a push in under 3
minutes. No time for intros. Let's get
into it. So, the US is now officially in
World War II. But to put it bluntly, US
entry into World War II required total
economic mobilization. That means all
the work needed to make cars, tanks, and
weapons will cause so much jobs, which
effectively will end the Great
Depression. And here's another part to
this. All the men are getting shipped
off to war. That means the people that
will step up to do this factory work
will mostly be women. That means during
the war, women had many new gains as
they took over male-dominated jobs.
However, it should be noted many women
were pushed out of the jobs after the
war when men returned. But women aren't
the only one that get opportunities.
African-Ameans do as well. They will
also work in factories. However, they
will face their own share of racism. But
the other people that get opportunities
here are immigrants and migrants. There
will be so much migration to big cities
that places like Los Angeles, Oakland,
Seattle, and Detroit will grow like
crazy. The specific immigrants I want to
mention here are Mexican ones [music]
because you start seeing a vast amount
of Mexican immigrants that entered the
US during the war under the Breretta
program which allowed Mexican laborers
to temporarily work in US agriculture
and railroad jobs. I'm sure you can
guess, but the response you'll see to
this is racism. An example of that is
the Zoot Sweet riots where Mexicans and
Filipinos were attacked in LA over a
series of days. And the last thing I
want to say is a lot of people like to
say FDR was one of the greatest
presidents. I won't really say anything
on the matter, but here is something
that doesn't look too good on his part.
During World War II, fear and racism led
FDR to issue an executive order which
would force around 120,000 Japanese
Americans into internment camps. And
these camps were not good in the
slightest. On the screen now are AP
style questions for this topic. Pause
now.
I'll put the answers on the screen now.
I will see you in the next one.